Finding Aid for Gloria Bennish collection, 1946-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Gloria Bennish collection 1946-1987
Bennish, Gloria.
87144 Aa 2
Founder of the University of Michigan Gilbert and Sullivan Society. Sound recordings (tape and disc) of productions, videocassettes, scrapbooks, slides, and posters.
10 linear feet
12 phonograph records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection came from the estate of Gloria Bennish (donor no. 7419 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Gloria Bennish was a founder of the Gilbert and Sullivan Society of the University of Michigan.
The Gloria Bennish collection consists of materials collected relating to the Gilbert and Sullivan Society. This includes photographic slides of productions, posters, sound tapes and sound discs of productions, and scrapbooks containing programs and photographs.
Subjects:
Gilbert, W. S. (William Schwenck), 1836-1911--Performances--Michigan.; Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900--Performances--Michigan.; University of Michigan. Gilbert and Sullivan Society.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Gilbert, W. S. (William Schwenck), 1836-1911--Performances--Michigan.; Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900--Performances--Michigan.; Operas and operettas.; Theatrical productions.; University of Michigan. Gilbert and Sullivan Society.; University of Michigan--Choral organizations.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Bennish, Gloria.; University of Michigan. Gilbert and Sullivan Society.; Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900--Performances--Michigan.; Gilbert, W. S. (William Schwenck), 1836-1911--Performances--Michigan.
Genre Terms:
Posters.; Scrapbooks.; Slides.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Gilbert and Sullivan Society materials
  - Slides of Gilbert and Sullivan Society productions, and of Society activities (Box 1)
  - Index to sound tapes of Gilbert and Sullivan Society productions (Box 2)
  - Sound tapes of Gilbert and Sullivan Society productions
    - Tapes no. 1-19 (Box 2)
    - Tapes no. 20-39 (Box 3)
    - Tapes no. 40-64 (Box 4)
    - Tapes no. 65-87 (Box 5)
    - Tapes no. 88-102 (Box 6)
    - Tapes no. 103-118 (Box 7)
      (also 3 unnumbered tapes)
  - Videocassette, VHS
    - Iolanthe April 1984 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbooks, 1946-1980, undated
    - 1946-1951 (Box 8)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 8)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 8)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - 1978-1980 (Box 9)
    - Undated, 2 volumes (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous programs (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous slides (Box 9)
  - Posters (Box 10)
    (include some D'Oyly Carte productions)
  - Disc Recordings
    - 1970 Yeomen of the Guard (Box 11)
      (transferred to UM Gilbert & Sullivan Society record group)
    - 1974, Iolanthe (Box 11)
    - 1975, Yeomen of the Guard (Box 11)
    - 1975, Pirates of Penzance (Box 11)
    - 1977, Patience (Box 11)
    - 1978, Gondoliers (Box 11)
    - 1978, Princess Ida (Box 11)
    - 1979, H.M.S. Pinafore (Box 11)
    - 1981, Utopia Limited (Box 11)
    - 1982, Patience (Box 11)
      (also cassette copy in box 7)
    - 1982, Gondoliers (Box 11)
      (missing as of November 1995)
    - 1983, Mikado (Box 11)
    - Disks duplicated in UM Gilbert & Sullivan Society record group (Box 12)